

Bastien Mussard

Software Engineer

➤ bastien.mussard@gmail.com

mussard.github.io

in/bastien-mussard

French national - 31 years old Resume produced on June 25, 2019 (Bold elements clickable)

Scientist by training, looking today for a job leaning more toward programming, which has effectively always been at the core of my work.

- Acustomed to work on cross-functional projects.
- Good dialog with people of broad backgrounds.
- Team work to launch new features, from creation to production phase.
- Communication on results and innovations, including through visual aids.

Creativity

Global thinking

Curiosity

Adaptability \(

Tenacity \

Team-player



EXPERIENCES

Postdoctorate

2017 - 2019

University of Colorado, Boulder, USA Contact: Sandeep Sharma

Lead a team of 4 PhD candidates. Handling of large operation and data flows. Design and creation of scalable algorithms. Set up good pratices and continuous integration.

Invited researcher

July 2016

University of Cornell, Ithaca, USA Contact: Cyrus Umrigar

Unified implementations to boost performance. Wrote user/developer docs for complex codes.

Research Engineer

2014 - 2017

Sorbonne University, Paris Contact: Julien Toulouse

Tasked with production and maintenance of codes. Optimized core routines in widely used algorithms. Developed user-friendly libraries for key tasks. Design and creation of naturally interfacing codes.



SKILLS

Linux, Bash, Unix				
Python				
C, C++			0	0
Git, SVN				0
Continuous Integration		0	0	0
Machine Learning		0	0	0

Bilingual French (native) and English (daily pratical use both personnally and professionally; lived 3 years in the United States).



PRODUCTION

15 scientific publications and significant contributions to major scientific codes:

- Molpro: a comprehensive system of commercial programs for advanced calculations.
- **Dice**: a modern code that takes advantage of the latest advances in the domain, written in C.
- **PySCF**: a theoretical chemistry program easy to use, coded in Python and C.
- **CHAMP**: a code that uses stochastic processes.



EDUCATION

PhD 2010 - 2013 Université de Lorraine, Nancy MSc2007 - 2010

École Normale Supérieure, Paris

Higher School Prep. Classes

2005 - 2007



INTERESTS

Teaching, Outreach, Swimming, Reading, Hiking